questions:
- number: 1
  question: 'Seat belts/safety harness must be worn, at all stages of flight, by:'
  answers:
    a: the pilot when she/he is the sole pilot.
    b: the occupants of both control seats.
    c: all on board during climb and descent.
    d: two children when they occupy a single seat.
  points: 1
- number: 2
  question: 'Civil Aviation Regulations require that turns onto final approach should:'
  answers:
    a: commence not below 500 ft AGL.
    b: be completed not below 500 ft AGL.
    c: be completed not closer than 500 metres from the aerodrome perimeter.
    d: be completed not closer than 500 metres from any displaced threshold.
  points: 1
- number: 3
  question: 'A pilot shall not consume any alcoholic liquor:'
  answers:
    a: 12 hours before departure of a flight.
    b: 24 hours before reporting for duty.
    c: 8 hours before reporting for duty.
    d: 8 hours before departure of the flight.
  points: 1
- number: 4
  question: 'The minimum horizontal distance from cloud for a fixed-wing aircraft,
    operating in class G airspace, is:'
  answers:
    a: 1,500 metres
    b: 1,500 ft
    c: 1,000 ft
    d: clear of cloud
  points: 1
- number: 5
  question: 'The fuel system in an aircraft must be checked for water contamination:'
  answers:
    a: before each flight.
    b: before the first flight of the day and after each refuling.
    c: before the first flight of the day and after the last flight of the day.
    d: at least once a day.
  points: 1
- number: 6
  question: 'One restriction placed on VFR aircraft, operating at or below 2,000 ft,
    is:'
  answers:
    a: minimum horizontal distance from cloud is 2,000 metres.
    b: minimum flight visibility is 6km.
    c: navigation must be by visual reference to the ground or water.
    d: minimum vertical distance from cloud is 1,000 ft.
  points: 1
- number: 7
  question: 'A student pilot is not permitted to carry passengers unless:'
  answers:
    a: he/she has completed 2 hours as pilot in command.
    b: he/she has passed the General Flying Progress Test and flies withing the student
      pilot area limits.
    c: he/she has completed 5 hours of cross-country flying.
    d: he/she has had a dual flight within the last 30 days.
  points: 1
- number: 8
  question: 'With local QNH set on the subscale, an altimeter will always read:'
  answers:
    a: pressure height
    b: density height.
    c: height above mean sea level.
    d: height above ground level.
  points: 1
- number: 9
  question: 'At a non-towered aerodrome, you should not continue an approach beyond
    the threshold until a preceeding light aeroplane, using the same runway, has:'
  answers:
    a: landed, and has vacated the runway, irrespective of the runway length, and
      is taxiing away.
    b: landed, and is at least 1,800 metres from the landing threshold.
    c: taken off and is at least 200 ft AGL.
    d: taken off and is at least 600 metres ahead of the landing threshold.
  points: 1
- number: 10
  question: 'You are to operate from a non-towered aerodrome where there is no ATIS
    and no other way of knowing the latest QNH. Before take-off, you should:'
  answers:
    a: set the altimeter to the aerodrome elevation.
    b: set the altimeter to read zero feet.
    c: set an approximate aerodrome pressure in the subscale.
    d: set 1013 hPa on the subscale.
  points: 1
- number: 11
  question: 'One item which must be included in the passenger briefing prior to take-off
    is:'
  answers:
    a: a demonstration of the correct crash landing position.
    b: the use and location of the fire extinguishers.
    c: the use and adjustment of the seat belts.
    d: the demonstration of evacuation procedures.
  points: 1
- number: 12
  question: With regard to the rules of the air in the CAR, which of the statements
    is correct?
  answers:
    a: An aircraft that is overtaking another aeroplane, has the right of way.
    b: If an aircraft and a glider are approaching head-on at approximately the same
      height the aeroplane must give way to the glider.
    c: An aircraft that is within 70 degree of the astern position of the aircraft
      ahead is considered an overtaking aircraft if its speed it greater.
    d: An aircraft that is overtaking another aircraft must do so by alterin its heading
      to the left.
  points: 1
- number: 13
  question: On which of the following types of flying is a passenger not permitted
    to be carried?
  answers:
    a: An aircraft engaged in aerobatic flying.
    b: Flying training given to a person who has not passed the General Flying Progress
      Test (GPFT).
    c: An aircraft carrying out formation flying.
    d: An aircraft engaged in search and rescue (SAR) operations.
  points: 1
- number: 14
  question: 'You are to carry out a flight from Parafield to the training area in
    a Piper Arrow - XYG. You are also in receipt of ATIS information "Charlie", indicating
    Runway 21 Right is being used. Your pre-taxi radio call will be:'
  answers:
    a: '"Parafield Ground, X-ray Yankee Golf, Piper Arrow, received Charlie, VFR to
      the training area, Runway 21 Right".'
    b: '"Parafield Ground, Piper Arrow X-ray Yankee Golf, for the Training Area, 
      Runway 21 Right, taxi clearance, received Charlie."'
    c: '"Parafield Ground, X-ray Yankee Golf, Runway 21 Right, for the Training Area, 
      received Charlie."'
    d: '"Parafield Ground, Piper Arrow X-ray Yankee Golf, taxi clearance for the 
      Training Area, Runway 21 Right, received Charlie.' 
  points: 1
- number: 15
  question: 'Area QNH is:'
  answers:
    a: the aerodrome pressure set in the altimeter before taxiing.
    b: the mean sea level pressure set the altimeter before taxiing.
    c: the local aerodrome pressure set in the altimeter while on navigation or cross-country
      flight.
    d: the mean sea level pressure set in the altimeter of the area over which the
      aircraft is flying while on navigation or cross-country exercise.
  points: 1
- number: 16
  question: 'When the aerodrome QNH is set, during taxi, the altimeter should read:'
  answers:
    a: zero.
    b: airfield elevation.
    c: vertical distance AGL.
    d: vertical distance AAL.
  points: 1
- number: 17
  question: 'One of the basic rules following an engine failure immediately after
    take-off is:'
  answers:
    a: always try to restart the engine.
    b: immdiately make a distress call.
    c: never turn back to the runway.
  points: 1
- number: 18
  question: 'A hard pull on the control column can cause an aeroplane to stall at
    almost any speed because:'
  answers:
    a: of reduced control effectiveness.
    b: the critical angle of attack can be exceeded.
    c: of decreased angle of attack.
    d: of reduced airspeed.
  points: 1
- number: 19
  question: 'A white dumb-bell symbol has been placed adjacent the primary wind indicator
    on your airfield. This means:'
  answers:
    a: the airfield is completely unserviceable.
    b: poor surface in this area, do not taxi here.
    c: parachute operations in progress.
    d: use hard surfaces only.
  points: 1
- number: 20
  question: 'An aircraft stall warning device will:'
  answers:
    a: indicate that a stall has occurred.
    b: cause a light to come on and a horn to sound after the aircraft stalls.
    c: indicate that the aircraft is approaching the stall at any attitude.
  points: 1

# Below are the solutions. Please don't read
solutions:
  1: a
  2: b
  3: d
  4: a
  5: b
  6: c
  7: b
  8: c
  9: a
  10: a
  11: c
  12: c
  13: b
  14: a
  15: d
  16: b
  17: c
  18: b
  19: d
  20: c